<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithmic Art on LTD Personal Website</title>
    <link>/tags/algorithmic-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithmic Art on LTD Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/algorithmic-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic art: &#39;Spiral Portal&#39;</title>
      <link>/2020/05/09/algorithmic-art-spiral-portal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/09/algorithmic-art-spiral-portal/</guid>
      <description>After enjoying Antonio Sánchez Chinchón’s DataCamp tutorial on using R and ggplot2 for algorithmic flower drawing based on Phyllotaxis, I decided to spend an afternoon exploring the techniques he covered. I extended the single flower techniques to a multi-flower image with each flower positioned to form an overall flower shape. The effect makes me think of a portal to a strange multicolor world.
A multicolor spiral portal image built in R and ggplot2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twinkling Starry Night with JS and Processing (Interactive)</title>
      <link>/2020/02/16/draw-twinkling-stars-with-javascript-and-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/16/draw-twinkling-stars-with-javascript-and-processing/</guid>
      <description>Background I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning about algorithmic art, which is a visual art genre that uses an algorithm (usually coded on a computer) to draw interesting or evocative images. While it is possible to do this in many languages, I decided to delve into the Processing language, which is a Java-style language and development environment that is specialised for visualisation.
What is this? This is an early casual output of that exploration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic art: &#39;Minimalist Rain&#39;</title>
      <link>/2020/02/01/algorithmic-art-minimalist-rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/01/algorithmic-art-minimalist-rain/</guid>
      <description>This was an early exploration of the basic functions of Processing. I rather liked the effect as a minimalist representation of rain.
Stylised representation of rain
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>